

Fernando Becerra Agredo

Cra 19a # 85-70 Apt 702, Bogotá - Colombia – Single Date of birth: August 11th 1984

DNI: 16376528 – Professional License Number: 76208-291060

Mobile Phone Number: +57 305 4112129 Skype ID: fernando.becerra.a

E-mail: fernando.becerra.a@gmail.com

Professional Profile

+15 years of experience working as a software developer, software and integration architect, tech lead and IT Manager. I have worked in banks, media and IT Companies in Colombia and USA (remotely), MSc in information technology architecture. Experience in Java 1.5, 8 and above, Spring framework, hibernate, SQL and No-Sql databases, SOA and microservice Architecture.

Excellent troubleshooting and analytical skills, well-organized, self-motivated, able to meet deadlines and handle multiple projects, and adapts to diverse teams and projects. SCRUM Master

Career Summary

Intraway SAS

Java Architect - Tech Manger Full-time Job December 2021 – Currently

Key Responsibilities:

Personnel management

- IT Couching
- IT Management
- Project management with Scrum methodology.
- Architecture Governance, Principles, technology decisions, and guidelines.
- PoC developments
- Apply microservice patterns
 - API Gateway
 - Circuit Breaker
 - Asynchronous Messaging
- Design of new versions of legacy systems to Java 11
- Design of solutions, creating architectural documents
 - Logical View
 - Process View
 - Development View
 - Physical View
 - Scenarios
- Apply Java patterns:
 - Creational Patterns
 - Structural Patterns
 - Behavioral Patterns
- Spring Boot Framework
- Spring Boot REST services
- TDD methodology with JUnit 5
- Java functional programming
- Time planning
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- AWS EC2
- Working with Agile Scrum/Kanban development methodology

Kibernum (Smart Start inc)

Java Architect
Full-time Job
June 2021 – December 2021

- IT Couching
- IT Lead
- Architecture Governance, Principles, technology decisions, and guidelines.
- PoC developments
- Apply microservice patterns

- API Gateway
- Circuit Breaker
- Asynchronous Messaging
- Design of new versions of legacy systems to Java 11
- Design of solutions, creating architectural documents
 - Logical View
 - Process View
 - Development View
 - Physical View
 - Scenarios
- Apply Java patterns:
 - Creational Patterns
 - Structural Patterns
 - Behavioral Patterns
- Spring Boot Framework
- Spring Boot REST services
- TDD methodology with JUnit 5
- Java functional programming
- Time planning
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- AWS EC2
- Working with Agile Scrum/Kanban development methodology

Globant (Disney - ESPN)

Software Designer Full-time Job March 2020 – June 2021

- IT Lead
- PoC developments
- Spring Boot Framework
- Spring Boot REST services
- TDD methodology with JUnit 5
- Java functional programming
- Time planning
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- AWS EC2
- Working with Agile Scrum/Kanban development methodology

SETI SAS (Alianza Fiduciaria)

Tech Lead Full-time Job September 2019 – February 2020

Key Responsibilities:

- Tech lead
- Personnel management
- IT Couching
- PoC developments
- Requirement writing
- Design integration of applications with Trivadis blueprints, Third party financial systems and Oracle Bus.
- Architecture Governance, Principles, technology decisions, and guidelines.
- Design of solutions, creating architectural documents
 - Logical View
 - Process View
 - Development View
 - Physical View
 - Scenarios
- Apply Java patterns:
 - Creational Patterns
 - Structural Patterns
 - Behavioral Patterns
- Project leadership
- AWS EC2
- Working with Agile Scrum development methodology as a Scrum Master.

Belatrix Software (FSE inc)

Software Engineer 3
Full-time Job
Junio 2018 – September 2019

- Java 8
- TDD methodology with JUnit4
- Design of solutions
- Time planning
- Spring Boot Framework
- Spring Boot REST services

- Spring Security
- Smart GWT

Periferia IT (ATH)

Senior II Full-time Job September 2017 – Junio 2018 Immediate Boss: Jamil Murcia

Key Responsibilities:

- Implementation of Java 1.5 Enterprise beans
- Apply Java patterns:
 - Creational Patterns
 - Structural Patterns
 - Behavioral Patterns
- JSF Framework
- Spring Boot Framework
- Hibernate Framework
- Implementation of JMS queues
- Designing and modifying reports using Jasper.
- Working with Agile Scrum development methodology as a Scrum developer.
- Tuning of SQL Queries
- Configuration of Maven projects
- TDD Programming
- Development of unit testing using JUnit4.
- Leadership of small projects

Tecnocom (ATH)

Senior III Full-time Job February 2017 – August 2017

- Deployments and configuration of JEE 1.5 web applications on WebLogic 12 Server.
- Implementation of EJB components.
- Apply Java patterns:
 - Creational Patterns
 - Structural Patterns

- Behavioral Patterns
- JSF Framework
- Spring Boot Framework
- Hibernate Framework
- Implementation of JMS queues
- Designing and modifying reports using Jasper.
- Working with Agile Scrum development methodology as a Scrum developer.
- Tuning of SQL Queries
- Configuration of Maven projects
- TDD Programming
- Development of unit testing using JUnit4.
- Leadership of small projects.

Intergrupo S.A.S

Software Engineer Full-time Job July 2015 – January 2017

Key Responsibilities:

- Deployments and configuration of JEE web applications on IBM WebSphere Server.
- Implementation of EJB components.
- Use of JSF framework in developing user interfaces implementing Richfaces.
- Spring MVC Framework
- Hibernate Framework
- Designing and modifying reports using Jasper.
- Working with Agile Scrum development methodology as a Scrum developer.
- TDD Programming
- Development of unit testing using JUnit4.

MMR Research

Survey Creator Full-time Job October 2014 – May 2015

- Program online surveys in ConfirmIT framework.
- Perform quality control testing for online surveys for appearance, logic, and data requirements

• Incorporate Images, video and other requested files into online surveys • Partner with project management, online panel and sales team • Provide input to create technical efficiencies within the programming team

Banco de Occidente – Credencial

Software Developer
Full-time Job
December 2011 – November 2013

Key Responsibilities:

- Design message flows in WebSphere for the new unified internet banking of "Grupo AVAL".
- Developing Web Services in JAVA.
- Specify requirements for integrating the internet core banking system with the core banking system FLEXCUBE
- Customize the current software of "Banco de Occidente" in order to interact with the new internet banking system, using C++ and PL/SQL languages.
- Approve Oracle ETL and ODS designs elaborated for third-party companies.
- Provide test data to the quality assurance team.
- Participate actively in the making decision meetings about the integration with the new Internet banking system.

Banco de Occidente - Credencial

Software Developer Full-time Job October 2008 – February 2011

Key Responsibilities:

- Review and discuss the functional requirements specifications for each project before starting programming.
- Develop PL/SQL and C++ software for new banking products such as "Recaudo Nacional de Planilla Asistida de Seguridad Social (PILA)" and interfaces for the SWIFT network.
- Design under UML methodology for new banking products and custom maintenance of applications.
- Support for production environments.

Casa de Bolsa del Grupo AVAL

Internship

October 2007 – April 2008.

Education

Universidad de los Andes

MScIT in Architecture March 2020

Pontificia Universidad Javeriana (Cali)

BSc in Computer Science and Systems Engineer October 2014

Scrum Team Member Accredited Certification™

International Scrum Institute™, License 29263936073519 July 2016

Scrum Certification for Java Developer™

International Scrum Institute™, License 57853741558268 May 2016

MongoDB University

M101 MongoDB for Java developers. 2016

Oracle University

Advanced PL/SQL: Oracle Database 10 June 2010

Oracle University

Oracle Database 10g: Develop PL/SQL Program Units June 2010

Languages

English, Advanced Level

IELTS General Test grade: 7.0

Kaplan International Colleges – Salisbury, United Kingdom

Advanced English
June 2014 – September 2014

Kaplan International Colleges – Sydney, Australia Higher Intermediate English March 2011 – September 2011